Lewis Morgans

Senior Software Engineering Contractor

PERSONAL SUMMARY

My name is Lewis Morgans. A Software Engineering Contractor focussing within web applications development. Using JavaScript, TypeScript, NgRx, RxJs, Angular 2+ and GraphQL as my day to day tools of development.

I'm a tech influencer with a great passion for coding. I code and study computer science intensively, mentoring other developers, writing technical content and sharing my passion for programming to over 3000 people on social media. I've worked with companies from large industry leaders to small scale startups. From Agile to Waterfall. Cloud-based to closed-circuit systems for international intelligence agencies. My experience within the industry makes me a perfect candidate to assist your company in accomplishing its goals.

WORK HISTORY

VQ Communications, Cardiff — Software Engineer

September 2020 - November 2020

Conference Manager - Involved with the UI team working within an Angular framework to provide a bespoke communications dashboard. Creating friendly user interaction for call management, resting on top of a .NET core and Cisco bridge. Heavy implementation of NgRx state management and RxJs Observables providing a powerful and scalable code base for clients operating in a close system environment such as the American department of defence, the Pentagon, SOCOM, the White House and several unnamed intelligence agencies.

Swift Media, Cardiff— Director / Contractor

March 2020 - Present

Admiral, Cardiff— Software Engineer

August 2018 - March 2020

InstaQuote; Involved in a large software delivery team with the target of reducing the customer journey time when applying for a home insurance quote. Opposed to 20 pages of information, we implemented a DVLA api to gather information about the clients home and repopulate the required quotation fields allowing the clients journey time to be cut dramatically, thus improving customer retention and overall sales. The application built within Angular 6 supported by a Java middle tier was my first project for Admiral.

QuoteEngine; Initially part of a small 4 man team, I was responsible with the code rewrite of the existing quote engine from a previous custom AngularJS implementation, to Angular 9. Starting as a proof of concept once we were able to prove the improved performance, efficiency and scalability of the new code base the team was then tripled in size to support a full rewrite. During this time we utilised state management NGRX and heavily leveraged the RXJS library. At my time of leaving the company the project was near it's completion with only automated testing remaining.

LINKEDIN:

www.linkedin.com/in/lewismorgansengineer

PERSONAL WEBSITE: www.weareswift.dev

GITHUB:

https://github.com/lewismorgans

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, TypeScript, Node.js, Next.js, GIT, Jasmine, Karma, Angular 2+, Express, ES6, REST API's, OOP/FP, RxJs, NgRx, Bootstrap 4.0. Unit Testing.

SOFT SKILLS

JIRA, ClickUp, Confluence, Communication, Time management, AGILE/SCRUM, Project management, Knowledge transfer.

REFERENCES

Available upon request.

Keytree, Port Talbot - Software Engineer

February 2018 - August 2018

TravelSafe; Subcontracted to British Petroleum, I acted within a medium sized team to deliver a mobile application built in Angular 5, using Ionic Cordova for native mobile usage. TravelSafe was in its infancy during my time on the project, supporting things such as a panic button, sending your GPS location to the BP main office. Helpful tips, such as not entering certain parts of town, avoiding tap water in certain countries etc. Designed for BP employees to manage their physical safety whilst travelling for work.

PERSONAL PROJECTS

Five, Three, Two, Go! — Software Engineer

Creation of a financial management application. Following the common budgeting practice known as the 50-30-20 rule, my application will allow users to register accounts, input their salaries and be met with an allowance of how much they can allocate to each section of the rule. The users can also input their actual expenditure and be notified by a seemingly pleasing UI of their over or under expenditure per section. The application is built within Angular v9 and supported via a Node/Express middle tier.

Pegasus — Software Engineer

Creation of a content management system. Using Angular 2 with a Node.JS backend to support persistent data through use of a user defined database link, such as MySQL, MongoDB etc.

GameShorts - Software Engineer

A web based video sharing application. Users can create and register accounts, upload videos, and share their game video libraries with friends. Currently in a stable Beta release for crowd testing and feedback. Designed as a place for gamers to share their favourite personal videos with a targeted audience.

EDUCATION

Cynffig Sixth Form College, Kenfig Hill

2008-2010 (A Level)

ICT

Business

Cynffig Comprehensive School, Kenfig Hill

2003-2010 (GCSE)

Maths
English Literature
English Language
Physics
Astro Physics
Chemistry
Design in digital applications